Guide to the South Africa Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
South Africa collection
1990-2014
1992-1996
MS 1559
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
33.81
(56 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material, audio recordings, and memorabilia relating to current political, economic, and social conditions in South Africa. The majority of the material pertains to the African National Congress and the first democratic election of April 27, 1994.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Arrangement
The original accession is arranged alphabetically by organization, title of publication, or personal name. A small section of subject files is included at the end of the accession. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The South Africa Collection consists of printed material arranged alphabetically by organization, name, personal name, or title of publication. A small number of subject files are included at the end of the collection. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Associated Materials
African Collection, MS 605; Pamphlet Collection, MS 1351; African Postcard Collection, MS 1575; South African Apartheid Collection, MS 1500; South African Poster Collection, MS 1574. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Copies of commercially produced audiovisual materials contained in this collection cannot be made for researcher use outside of the repository.
Anti-apartheid movements -- South Africa; Apartheid -- South Africa; Democracy -- South Africa; Elections -- South Africa; Voting -- South Africa; South Africa -- Economic conditions; South Africa -- Politics and government; South Africa -- Social conditions; Mandela, Nelson, 1918-2013; African National Congress; World Conference against Racism, Racial Discrimination, Xenophobia, and Related Intolerance ( 2001 Durban, South Africa)
- Original accession, 1990-1997
  - The Africa Fund, New York
    - General [newsletters, reports, fundraising appeals, memoranda, etc.]
      - 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Africa Fund News, 1993, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Election Watch, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Perspectives, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "Stop Apartheid's Violence" [campaign initiated by Africa Fund], 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Unlock Apartheid's Jails" [campaign initiated by Africa Fund], 1992 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Africa Institute of South Africa, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Africa Muslim Party (A. M. P.), [1994?], undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    General note
    See also: South Africa Collection, 1990-1997 (inclusive), 1992-1996 (bulk) Folder 223
    See also: South Africa Collection, 1990-1997 (inclusive), 1992-1996 (bulk) Folder 336
  - African-American Labor Center (AALC)/AFL-CIO, Washington D.C., 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - African-European Institute (AEI)
    See: South Africa Collection, 1990-1997 (inclusive), 1992-1996 (bulk) Folder 246
  - African Christian Democratic Party (ACDP), [1994?], undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The African Post, London, 1992 May-July (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - African National Congress (ANC)
    - General [applications, subscription forms, list of departments], 1992-1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Archives, University of Fort Hare, 1996, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Budget, 1992, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      General
      See also: South Africa Collection, 1990-1997 (inclusive), 1992-1996 (bulk) Folder 42
    - Campaign for Peace and Democracy, [1992] (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Conferences [not all inclusive; listed chronologically]
      - National Conference (48th) [adoption of the constitution of the ANC], 1991 July (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - National [Policy] Conference [produced "Ready to Govern: an Introduction to the ANC's Policy Guidelines"], 1992 May 28-31 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - International Solidarity Conference ["From Apartheid to Peace, Democracy, and Development"] Johannesburg, 1993 February 19-21 (Box 1, Folder 19 - 20)
      - National Consultative Conference on Regional Policy, 1993 March (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Culture and Development Conference (CDC), 1993 April 25-May 2 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Land Redistribution Options [Conference on], 1993 October 12-15 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - First National Conference on Education, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - National Reconstruction and Strategy Conference, 1994 January 21-23 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - National Conference (49th), Bloemfontein, 1994 December 17-21 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - National Constitutional Conference ["Building a United Nation: Policy Proposals for the Final Constitution"], 1995 March 31-April 2 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Constitutional Committee
      - Policy guides, procedures on the constitution making process, 1991 Apr, 1992 March-October (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Bill of Rights, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Department of Arts and Culture, 1992, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Department of International Affairs, 1993 Oct, 1994 December (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Development Programmes Centre (DPC), undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Economic policy [model for human development, most likely ANC], [1994?] (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Education Department, 1994 Jan, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Election/voting materials, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 35 - 36)
      - Election/voting materials, 1994-1995, undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - Elections Commission, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - Electoral List [profiles of the top fifty candidates of the ANC national list], 1994 January 25 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - Environmental policy [toxic waste], 1994 February (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - Executive Committees [branch], [1994] (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - Government of National Unity, 1995 October (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Health Department, 1992 Oct, 1994 Jan, May, undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - Human Resources Development, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - Interim Science and Technology Group, 1990 November 24 (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - Land and Agricultural Desk/Land Commission, 1992 Feb, 1993 Aug, undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
      - Language policy
        - Afrophone Translation Project [includes ANC policy considerations, 1992], 1993 (Box 3, Folder 47)
        - "South Africa's New Language Policy", [1994?] (Box 3, Folder 48)
      - Lawyers, 1993 Oct, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
      - Mandela, Nelson
        - Biographical material [listed chronologically], 1993-1996 (Box 3, Folder 50)
        - Speeches, 1992-1994, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - Mayibuye: Journal of the African National Congress, 1993 Oct, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
      - Memorial tributes [primarily Oliver Tambo and Chris Hani], 1993 (Box 3, Folder 53)
      - Mineral and energy policy, 1994 January 28, November 12-13, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
      - Mission to the United States, [1993 Feb?] (Box 4, Folder 55)
      - " Mzabalazo": A pictorial History of the African National Congress, 1994 May (Box 4, Folder 56)
      - Natal [briefing notes on visit to the region], 1994 March 5-6 (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - National Executive Committee, 1992-1996, undated (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - National Negotiations Consultative Forum [working documents], 1993 June 26-27 (Box 4, Folder 59)
      - National Social Welfare and Development Plan, 1994 Nov, 1996 February (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - National Tripartite Alliance [National Day of Action in Defense of Democracy], 1993 July 1 (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - Negotiations Commission, 1992 Sep, 1993 February-Nov, undated (Box 4, Folder 62)
        See also: South Africa Collection, 1990-1997 (inclusive), 1992-1996 (bulk) Folder 308
      - News/press briefings
        - 1992, Jan 2-4, 6-8, 13 (Box 4, Folder 63)
        - 1992, Feb 2, 13-14 (Box 4, Folder 64)
        - 1992 Feb 17-20 (Box 4, Folder 65)
        - 1992 Feb 21, 24-25 (Box 4, Folder 66)
        - 1992 Feb 26-28 (Box 4, Folder 67)
        - 1992 Mar 2, 6, 10 (Box 5, Folder 68)
        - 1992 Mar 13, 19-20, 23 (Box 5, Folder 69)
        - 1992 Mar 24-26 (Box 5, Folder 70)
        - 1992 Mar 27, 31 (Box 5, Folder 71)
        - 1992 Apr 1, 3, 7-8 (Box 5, Folder 72)
        - 1992 Apr 9-10, 13-14 (Box 5, Folder 73)
        - 1992 Apr 16, 23-24 (Box 5, Folder 74)
        - 1992 Apr 27-30 (Box 6, Folder 75)
        - 1992 May 8, 14, 19, 21 (Box 6, Folder 76)
        - 1992 Jun 11-12, 15, 17, 22 (Box 6, Folder 77)
        - 1992 Jun 23-25 (Box 6, Folder 78)
        - 1992 Jul 1-3 (Box 6, Folder 79)
        - 1992 Jul 7-8, 10 (Box 6, Folder 80)
        - 1992 Jul 13-15 (Box 6, Folder 81)
        - 1992 Jul 16, 20-22 (Box 6, Folder 82)
        - 1992 Jul 23-24, 27 (Box 6, Folder 83)
        - 1992 Jul 29-31 (Box 7, Folder 84)
        - 1992 Aug 17-20 (Box 7, Folder 85)
        - 1992 Aug 21, 24-26 (Box 7, Folder 86)
        - 1992 Aug 27-28, 31 (Box 7, Folder 87)
        - 1992 Sep 1-4 (Box 7, Folder 88)
        - 1992 Sep 7-10 (Box 7, Folder 89)
        - 1992 Sep 11, 14-15 (Box 7, Folder 90)
        - 1992 Sep 16-18 (Box 8, Folder 91)
        - 1992 Sep 21-23 (Box 8, Folder 92)
        - 1992 Sep 24-25 (Box 8, Folder 93)
        - 1992 Sep 28-29 (Box 8, Folder 94)
        - 1992 Sep 30 (Box 8, Folder 95)
        - 1992 Oct 1-2 (Box 8, Folder 96)
        - 1992 Oct 5-8 (Box 8, Folder 97)
        - 1992 Oct 9, 12, 14-15 (Box 8, Folder 98)
        - 1992 Oct 16, 19-21 (Box 9, Folder 99)
        - 1992 Oct 22-23, 28 (Box 9, Folder 100)
        - 1992 Oct 30 (Box 9, Folder 101)
        - 1992 Nov 2-6 (Box 9, Folder 102)
        - 1992 Nov 10-13 (Box 9, Folder 103)
        - 1992 Nov 16-19 (Box 9, Folder 104)
        - 1992 Nov 20, 23-25 (Box 9, Folder 105)
        - 1992 Nov 27, 30 (Box 9, Folder 106)
        - 1992 Dec 1-3 (Box 10, Folder 107)
        - 1992 Dec 4, 7-8, 10 (Box 10, Folder 108)
        - 1992 Dec 17-18, 21 (Box 10, Folder 109)
        - 1993 Jan 5-8 (Box 10, Folder 110)
        - 1993 Jan 11-14 (Box 10, Folder 111)
        - 1993 Jan 15-17, 19, 21-22 (Box 10, Folder 112)
        - 1993 Jan 25-27, 29 (Box 10, Folder 113)
        - 1993 Feb 1, 4-5 (Box 10, Folder 114)
        - 1993 Feb 8-11 (Box 11, Folder 115)
        - 1993 Feb 12, 15-17 (Box 11, Folder 116)
        - 1993 Feb 18-19 (Box 11, Folder 117)
        - 1993 Apr 2, 5 (Box 11, Folder 118)
        - 1993 Apr 23 (Box 11, Folder 119)
        - 1993 Apr 29 (Box 11, Folder 120)
        - 1993 Apr 30 (Box 11, Folder 121)
        - 1993 May 4, 6-8 (Box 11, Folder 122)
        - 1993 May 9-10, 12-13 (Box 11, Folder 123)
        - 1993 May 14, 18-19, 21 (Box 12, Folder 124)
        - 1993 May 25-26 (Box 12, Folder 125)
        - 1993 Jun 1-4, 10 (Box 12, Folder 126)
        - 1993 Jun 11, 18, 22 (Box 12, Folder 127)
        - 1993 Jun 23, 25, 29-30 (Box 12, Folder 128)
        - 1993 Jul 1-2, 5-6 (Box 12, Folder 129)
        - 1993 Jul 8-9, 14-15 (Box 12, Folder 130)
        - 1993 Jul 16, 19, 21-22 (Box 12, Folder 131)
        - 1993 Jul 26-27 (Box 13, Folder 132)
        - 1993 Aug 1-2, 17-19 (Box 13, Folder 133)
        - 1993 Aug 20, 23 (Box 13, Folder 134)
        - 1993 Aug 24, 26, 31 (Box 13, Folder 135)
        - 1993 Sep 3, 7-8 (Box 13, Folder 136)
        - 1993 Sep 9, 13-14 (Box 13, Folder 137)
        - 1993 Sep 15-16, 20-21 (Box 13, Folder 138)
        - 1993 Sep 22-24, 27 (Box 13, Folder 139)
        - 1993 Sep 29-30 (Box 13, Folder 140)
        - 1993 Oct 1, 4-6 (Box 13, Folder 141)
        - 1993 Oct 7, 11, 13 (Box 14, Folder 142)
        - 1993 Oct 14-15 (Box 14, Folder 143)
        - 1993 Oct 18-19 (Box 14, Folder 144)
        - 1993 Oct 20, 22 (Box 14, Folder 145)
        - 1993 Oct 25-27 (Box 14, Folder 146)
        - 1993 Oct 29 (Box 14, Folder 147)
        - 1993 Nov 2-4 (Box 14, Folder 148)
        - 1993 Nov 5, 8-9 (Box 14, Folder 149)
        - 1993 Nov 11-12, 17 (Box 14, Folder 150)
        - 1993 Nov 18-19, 22 (Box 15, Folder 151)
        - 1993 Nov 23-25 (Box 15, Folder 152)
        - 1993 Nov 26, 29-30 (Box 15, Folder 153)
        - 1993 Dec 1-3, 6 (Box 15, Folder 154)
        - 1993 Dec 7-9 (Box 15, Folder 155)
        - 1993 Dec 10-13 (Box 15, Folder 156)
        - 1993 Dec 14, 17 (Box 15, Folder 157)
        - 1994 Jan 1, 4, 6-7 (Box 15, Folder 158)
        - 1994 Jan 10-14 (Box 15, Folder 159)
        - 1994 Jan 17, 19-21 (Box 15, Folder 160)
        - 1994 Jan 24, 26-28, 31 (Box 16, Folder 161)
        - 1994 Feb 3-4, 7-8, 11 (Box 16, Folder 162)
        - 1994 Feb 14-18 (Box 16, Folder 163)
        - 1994 Feb 21, 23-25 (Box 16, Folder 164)
        - 1994 Mar 1-4 (Box 16, Folder 165)
        - 1994 Mar 7-11 (Box 16, Folder 166)
        - 1994 Mar 18, 23, 28, 30-31 (Box 16, Folder 167)
        - 1994 Apr 8, 12-13, 15 (Box 16, Folder 168)
        - 1994 Apr 18-22 (Box 17, Folder 169)
        - 1994 Apr 25-26, 29 (Box 17, Folder 170)
        - 1994 May 11, 24-25 (Box 17, Folder 171)
        - 1994 Jun 1, 3, 6-7, 9-10, 13 (Box 17, Folder 172)
        - 1994 Jun 14, 21-27 (Box 17, Folder 173)
      - Newspapers
        - African National Congress Newsletter [published by the ANC mass communications section], 1992 (Box 17, Folder 174)
        - ANC People's Voice/Xtra [publications of the Western Cape], 1994 Mar, undated (Box 17, Folder 175)
        - Amandla [published by the Pretoria Witwaterstrand Vereeniging (PWV) region of the ANC], 1992 Oct, Nov, 1993 Apr, September-Oct, 1994 January-February (Box 17, Folder 176)
        - Congress Militant: Paper of the Marxist Workers' Tendency of the ANC, 1994 March 21 (Box 17, Folder 177)
        - Hlanganani [mouthpiece of the ANC Northern OFS region], 1993 (Box 17, Folder 178)
        - The Observer [issued by ANC Western Transvaal region], 1993 October (Box 17, Folder 179)
        - The Voice [official newsletter of the ANC Northern Cape region], 1994 July (Box 17, Folder 180)
      - Parliamentary organization, 1993 October 26 (Box 17, Folder 181)
      - Police [discussion papers], 1993 (Box 17, Folder 182)
      - Political Education Section, undated (Box 17, Folder 183)
      - Press releases/statements
        - 1991 Dec (Box 17, Folder 184)
        - 1992 Jan (Box 17, Folder 185)
        - 1992 Feb (Box 17, Folder 186)
        - 1992 Mar (Box 17, Folder 187)
        - 1992 Apr (Box 17, Folder 188)
        - 1992 May (Box 17, Folder 189)
        - 1992 Jun (Box 17, Folder 190)
        - 1992 Jul (Box 17, Folder 191)
        - 1992 Aug (Box 17, Folder 192)
        - 1992 Sep (Box 17, Folder 193)
        - 1992 Oct (Box 18, Folder 194)
        - 1992 Nov (Box 18, Folder 195)
        - 1992 Dec (Box 18, Folder 196)
        - 1993 Jan 5-14 (Box 18, Folder 197)
        - 1993 Jan 15-29 (Box 18, Folder 198)
        - 1993 Feb (Box 18, Folder 199)
        - 1993 Mar (Box 18, Folder 200)
        - 1993 Apr (Box 18, Folder 201)
        - 1993 May (Box 18, Folder 202)
        - 1993 Jun (Box 18, Folder 203)
        - 1993 Jul (Box 18, Folder 204)
        - 1993 Aug (Box 18, Folder 205)
        - 1993 Sep (Box 18, Folder 206)
        - 1993 Oct 1-15 (Box 19, Folder 207)
        - 1993 Oct 18-31 (Box 19, Folder 208)
        - 1993 Nov (Box 19, Folder 209)
        - 1993 Dec (Box 19, Folder 210)
        - 1994 Jan (Box 19, Folder 211)
        - 1994 Feb (Box 19, Folder 212)
        - 1994 Mar (Box 19, Folder 213)
        - 1994 Apr (Box 19, Folder 214)
        - 1994 May (Box 19, Folder 215)
        - 1994 Jun (Box 19, Folder 216)
        - 1994 Jul (Box 19, Folder 217)
        - 1994 Aug (Box 19, Folder 218)
        - n.d. (Box 19, Folder 219)
      - Pretoria Witwatersrand Vereeniging (PWV) [briefing notes on visit to Gauteng], 1994 February 26-27 (Box 20, Folder 220)
      - Prisoners/detainees
      - "Report of the [Internal]Commission of Enquiry into Complaints by Former African National Congress Prisoners and Detainees" [see also: Amnesty International], 1992 August (Box 20, Folder 221)
      - "Report of the [Motsuenyane] Commission of Enquiry into Certain Allegations of Cruelty and Human Rights Abuse against ANC Prisoners and Detainees by ANC Members", 1993 August 20 (Box 20, Folder 222)
      - Reconstruction and Development Program (RDP)
        - General [discussion documents, basic guide], 1994 January, 1996 January-Feb, undated (Box 20, Folder 223)
        - Council for the Environment [report on implementation of the RDP], 1994-1995 (Box 20, Folder 224)
        - Ministry for Welfare and Population Development, 1995 April (Box 20, Folder 225)
        - Science and technology policy [report sponsored by the International Development Research Centere], 1992 December (Box 20, Folder 226)
        - Sports Desk, [1992?], undated (Box 20, Folder 227)
        - Transition to Democracy Act [discussion document], 1992 (Box 20, Folder 228)
        - Umkhonto We Sizwe [Spear of the Nation, the military wing of the ANC], 1993 September 3-4 (Box 20, Folder 229)
        - United Nations Security Council [presentation to], 1992 July 15 (Box 20, Folder 230)
        - Video Unit, undated (Box 20, Folder 231)
        - Western Transvaal Region, 1995 May 30 (Box 20, Folder 232)
        - Women's League, [1990 Aug?], 1992 Mar, May, 1993 February (Box 20, Folder 233)
        - Youth League/ Horizon: Journal of ANC Youth League, 1992 Oct, 1993 Jan, Apr, undated (Box 20, Folder 234)
  - African Peoples Democratic Union of South Africa (APDUSA), 1993 December-1994 March (Box 21, Folder 235)
  - Africare, Washington D.C., undated (Box 21, Folder 236)
  - Afrikaner-Volksfront, 1994 July (Box 21, Folder 237)
  - The Aida Parker Newsletter, 1993 March (Box 21, Folder 238)
  - The American Committee on Africa (ACOA), New York, 1992-1993, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 239)
    See also: South Africa Collection, 1990-1997 (inclusive), 1992-1996 (bulk) Folder 1
  - American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations (AFL-CIO), Washington, D. C., 1992 February-1995 February (Box 21, Folder 240)
  - Amnesty International, London, New York, 1992 Jul, December (Box 21, Folder 241)
  - Anglican Students' Federation (ASF), 1993 January (Box 21, Folder 242)
  - Anti-Apartheid Movement (AA) [London], 1992 March-1993 Aug, undated (Box 21, Folder 243)
  - Anti-Censorship Action Group of South Africa (ACAG), 1992 January-1993 (Box 21, Folder 244)
  - Association of Concerned African Scholars (ACAS), Washington D.C., 1992 June-1993 March (Box 21, Folder 245)
  - Association of Western European Parliamentarians for Action Against Apartheid (AWEPAA), 1992 February (Box 21, Folder 246)
  - The Azanian Labour Journal, 1992 July (Box 21, Folder 247)
  - Azanian People's Liberation Army (APLA), 1992 (Box 21, Folder 248)
  - Black Sash, 1992 Oct, 1994-1995 (Box 21, Folder 249)
  - Border Rural Committee (BRC), 1993 March-1996 April (Box 21, Folder 250)
  - British Defence and Aid Fund for Southern Africa, London, 1992, undated (Box 21, Folder 251)
  - The Built Environment Action Movement (BEAM), 1994 January (Box 21, Folder 252)
  - Canada-South Africa Cooperation (CSAC), Ottawa [Canada-Afrique du Sud], 1992 (Box 21, Folder 253)
  - The Canon Collins Educational Trust Fund, London, 1995 March (Box 21, Folder 254)
  - Cape Teachers' Professional Association (CTPA), 1993 June (Box 21, Folder 255)
  - Cape Town Business and Professional Women's Club, undated (Box 21, Folder 256)
  - Centre for Constitutional Analysis, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 257)
  - Centre for Development Analysis (CDA), 1993 (Box 21, Folder 258)
  - Centre for Development Studies (CDS) [includes Project Vote, in association with Matla Trust], 1992-1994, undated (Box 21, Folder 259)
  - Centre for Intergroup Studies (CIS)
    - 21st Anniversary Review, 0 (Box 21, Folder 260)
    - Track Two [publication of the CIS], 1992-1996 (Box 21, Folder 261)
  - Chamber of Mines of South Africa (CM), 1994 (Box 21, Folder 262)
  - Charles Steward Mott Foundation, Michigan, 1994 (Box 21, Folder 263)
  - Child Welfare Society, undated (Box 21, Folder 264)
  - Civil Rights League, 1992 February (Box 21, Folder 265)
  - Commissions of Inquiry
    - DeMeyer, 1992 (Box 21, Folder 266)
    - Goldstone
      - 1992 Jun 24 (Box 21, Folder 267)
      - 1992 Oct 27 (Box 22, Folder 268)
      - 1992 Dec 21 (Box 22, Folder 269)
      - 1993 Dec 3 (Box 22, Folder 270)
    - Parson's Commission/KwaNdebele, 1992 (Box 22, Folder 271)
  - Commonwealth Currents, London, 1992 January-Nov, 1994 February-July (Box 22, Folder 272)
  - Commonwealth Observer Mission to South Africa (COMSA), London, Johannesburg, 1992 October-1993 May (Box 22, Folder 273)
  - Community Law Centre (CLC), 1992 Jun, 1993 Sep, December (Box 22, Folder 274)
  - Comrades for a Workers Government, 1993 May-Jun, 1994 Apr, undated (Box 22, Folder 275)
  - Confederation of South African Students (COSAS), 1991-1993 (Box 22, Folder 276)
  - Congress of South African Trade Unions (COSATU), 1992-1994, undated (Box 22, Folder 277)
  - Conservative Party (CP), 1993 April-June (Box 22, Folder 278)
  - "Constitution of the Republic of South Africa" [draft; includes combined reports of Technical Committee], 1993 (Box 22, Folder 279)
  - Constitutional Talk [official newsletter of the Constitutional Assembly], 1996 (Box 22, Folder 280)
  - Convention for a Democratic South Africa (CODESA) [first plenary session], 1991 December 20-21 (Box 22, Folder 281)
  - Coordinating Committee on VAT, undated (Box 23, Folder 282)
  - Court of Common Council, Connecticut, 1992 March (Box 23, Folder 283)
  - Covert Action, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 284)
  - Democratic Party (DP), 1992-1995, undated (Box 23, Folder 285)
  - Department of Defense, U.S. [The National Security Education Act (NSAE)/The Boren Bill], 1992 May (Box 23, Folder 286)
  - Department of Foreign Affairs/ Focus, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 287)
  - Dikwankwetla Party of South Africa (DPSA), undated (Box 23, Folder 288)
  - Disabled People South Africa (DPSA), London, South Africa, 1995 January (Box 23, Folder 289)
  - Eastern Cape [report by Bantu Holomisa, Transkei, on civil unrest in black communities], 1993 March (Box 23, Folder 290)
  - Election Information and Research Consortium (EIRC), 1995 Jun, undated (Box 23, Folder 291)
  - Embassy of South Africa, Washington, D.C., 1992-1994 (Box 23, Folder 292)
  - End Loans to South Africa (ELTSA), London, 1992, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 293)
  - English Resource Unit (ERU), London, 1993 July (Box 23, Folder 294)
  - Episcopal Churchpeople for a Free Southern Africa (ECSA), New York
    - 1992 Jan-1993 Dec (Box 23, Folder 295)
    - 1994 Feb-1997 (Box 23, Folder 296)
  - Federal Party (FP), undated (Box 23, Folder 297)
  - Federasie van Afrikaanse Kultuurvereniginge, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 298)
  - The Foundation for Peace and Democracy, 1993 Dec, 1994 March (Box 23, Folder 299)
  - Freedom Front/Vryheidsfront, 1994 Apr, 1995 May, undated (Box 23, Folder 300)
  - The Green Party (GRP), 1994, undated (Box 23, Folder 301)
  - Group Information Service, 1992 (Box 23, Folder 302)
  - Harvard University, 1992 September (Box 23, Folder 303)
  - The Helen Suzman Foundation, 1995 Dec, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 304)
  - Holland Committee on Southern Africa, Amsterdam, 1993 February (Box 23, Folder 305)
  - Human Rights Commission (HRC), 1992 January-Sep, 1994 Feb, undated (Box 23, Folder 306)
  - Impact, 1992 February (Box 24, Folder 307)